Soma Veszelovszki

5+ years of software engineering experience in **fast-paced startup** environments.

Strong passion for clean and maintainable code.

Constant drive to **expand skill set** and have a **comprehensive understanding** of projects, ambition to **manage teams**.

Looking for a company with a **meaningful product**, **relatable core values**, and a good **work-life balance**.

EXPERIENCE

<u>Maverick Derivatives</u> / trading company (Netherlands) Backend Developer [C++]

MAY 2021 - JAN 2023

Built and maintained a trading server managing 200k instruments, responsible for 30% of all company trades in the domain. Learned how to handle stress well. Received a 120% performance review after learning period – proudest career achievement so far.

aiMotive / self-driving startup (Hungary) Software Engineer [C, C++]

JUL 2017 - APR 2021

Developed generic mathematical types and algorithms, resulting in 65% faster GPU execution. Created a media library recording 100+GB of videos every day. Refactored the software-to-car interface and added support for 4 times more car platforms. Built a desktop application for monitoring and controlling the car.

funiQ / active tourism website (Hungary) Full-Stack & Android Developer [JavaScript, php, Java]

JUN 2016 - JUL 2017

Implemented a photo upload web page and a markup text editor. Built the Android <u>application</u> for the site from scratch.

EDUCATION

Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Electrical Engineering Master's Degree (summa cum laude)

SEP 2014 - JAN 2021

SIDE PROJECTS

Babocar [C++, Node.js, React]

Complete hardware, software, and monitoring web application for a self-driving car. In 2021, it broke the all-time <u>lap record</u> at the RobonAUT autonomous car race.

Mondrian in Random [Kotlin]

Android <u>application</u> for generating random Mondrian-style pictures and setting them as wallpaper.

Located in EU (Hungary)

Email soma.veszelovszki@gmail.com

Web <u>soma.veszelovszki.hu</u>

GitHub github.com/somaveszelovszki

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/soma-veszelovszki

TECHNOLOGIES

C/C++, TypeScript, Java, Kotlin, Python

Boost, GTest, GMock, CMake, Conan

Node.js, React, Bootstrap, jQuery

Rest APIs, Google Protobuf, Kafka

Docker, Android, ROS, FreeRTOS

MySQL, Postgres, Datadog, Liquibase

Vuforia Augmented Reality SDK

GitLab CI/CD, Ansible

SKILLS

Enthusiastic proactiveness

Autonomy and ownership

Critical thinking and problem solving

Strong work ethic and dependability

Quick understanding of new concepts

Effective communication

LANGUAGES

English (proficient)

Hungarian (native)

HOBBIES

Preferring active ways to spend time. Favorites are **hiking** or **biking** with family, **ice hockey** during winter season, and recently took up **climbing**.